# 佛山·顺德
Fo Shan, shun de
# 哈喽 雪鱼今天在顺德的均安镇
Hello, xue yu at at junan town today in shunde
# 来这边呢
We came here
# 主要是为了一个当地比较特色的美食-蒸猪
For a very specific local food - steamed whole pig
# 它的特别之处呢 是把一整头猪
The specific point is steamed a whole pig
# 上蒸屉来蒸
On a steam tray
# 在过去只有在一些红白喜事上
In the past you only can eat it
# 祭祀活动上 才能吃得到
At some worship festival
# 现在呢 在平常的时候也能吃得到
We can eat at normal time
# 今天咱们来的地方是一个
We came to a farm town
# 叫大板桥的农庄
Named dabanqiao” village
# 这个农庄就是以做蒸猪而出名
This farm town is famous of steamed whole pig
# 前面就是做蒸猪的地方
In the front that’s the place where they make steamed pig
# 我们能看到一匹猪摊在桌子上
We can see a pig
# 这个肉切的就像芒果一样
Its cutting like how we cutting mongo
# 但是皮还是连着的
But with skin connected
# 好香啊
Very fragment it smells
# 师傅里面放的是五香粉吗
Shifu is there “wuxiang” powder
# 对 五香粉 白糖这些
Yeah “wuxiang” powder and white sugar
# 就这样完成了腌制
That’s how they pickled a pig
猪已经上了蒸屉 开始炖起来
# 猪处理好之后 再上蒸屉蒸
They steamed the pig after pickled
# 我听说 还会用钢针插猪皮是吧
I heard they used steel needle to poke pig skin
# 等猪蒸到大概35分钟的时候
After steamed the pig for 35 minutes
# 我们就打开盖子
We will open the cover of steamer
# 然后用扎针扎猪皮
And then use steel needle to poke pig skin
# 松一下皮
Make the pig skin loose a little bit
# 等油冒出来
Wash it
# 流出来 然后用清水冲洗
After oil  flow out
# 这么吃起来 口感会更好 不油腻
It make better texture of pork, with less oily
# 不油腻 还有皮爽 肉滑
Unoily and smooth skin and tender meat
# 猪已经上蒸屉半个小时了
The pig is steaming for 30 minutes already
# 肉香都被热气带出来了
Good smell of pork is carried by hot air
# 闻着味 谁能不馋呢
Anyone will be hungry when they smell it
# 120斤的猪肉 最后能剩多少斤
How many pounds of meat will left after processed a 120 pounds pig
# 去骨头去内脏，大概60多斤吧
About 60 pounds after take off bones and internal organs
# 差不多一半
About half
# 哇
Wow
# （猪：我就是这么找人稀罕）
That's why people love me
# 拍照可能比吃更吸引人
Most People prefer to take pictures but eat
今天可能是有谁在组织宴会吧
坐了好多桌的人
看完了剁蒸猪 咱们接下来就是
# 坐下来吃点饭
Lets sit down and eat something
# 这个是咱们要的蒸猪
This is our steamed pork
# 刚才小哥拿来的时候
Little brother put a heater at the bottom
# 然后在下面放了一个加热的东西
When he get us the steamed whole pig
# 现在蒸猪 冒着热气
Now steamed whole pig is
# 会不会感觉更香呢
Will it taste better?
# 咱们尝一个
Lets try it
# 上面还点缀着白芝麻
It covered by white sesame
# 这个白芝麻很特别
White sesame is pretty special
# 放在上面 你会感觉到很好看
You will feel it looks better
# 好了 我们吃完了
Okay, we finished eat now
# 这顿饭老板本来
Chef want to
# 打算要请我们的
Pay us on this meal
# 后来呢 我也不知道它具体是多少钱
I don’t know how much it is exactly
# 所以说 给了150块钱转头就跑
So we give him 150 yuan and run away
# 当然呢 也感谢老板给了我们这个机会
Of course, thanks to chef to give us the chance to eat steamed whole pig
# 让我们看一看
Let us take a look
# 蒸猪这种特色美食是怎么做的
how they cook
# 吃的很开心 那肉肉长的呢
They are happy to eat, grow some meat
# 它自己也很开心
The pig is happy too
# 好了 这么晚了 我们要走了  拜拜
Okay, its very night, we gonna go, bye!
# 关 注 雪 鱼 探 店